《指定幸存者》前情提要
Previously on "Designated Survivor"...
国会大厦遭到袭击  总统死了
The Capitol's been attacked. Eagle is gone.
-整个国会  内阁  -天啊
- Congress, the Cabinet. - Oh, oh, my God.
先生  你现在是美国总统了
Sir, you are now the President.
我收到了一份国防部的高度机密文件
I received a highly classified DOD file
里面详细描述了如何炸毁国会大厦
detailing how to blow up the Capitol.
我觉得白宫里有内鬼
I think there's a traitor in the White House.
我得避开那些
I had to put down everyone's name
亚伦·肖尔
有足够安全等级的人
who had security clearance.
亚伦也在名单上
Aaron's on this list.
国会大厦爆炸  里面所有人都死了
The Capitol blew up and everyone died
唯独彼得·麦克利什议员生还
except Congressman Peter MacLeish.
他脱不了干系
He's in on it.
你愿意当副总统吗
How does vice president sound to you?
我不胜荣幸
I would be honored.
这恰恰是我们一直以来奋斗的目标
This is exactly what we've been working for.
但牺牲了多少呢
But at what cost?
只要值得  无论代价
At any cost necessary.
彼得·麦克利什和中情局头号通缉的雇佣兵
Peter MacLeish and the CIA's most wanted mercenary
中情局报告
内斯特·洛萨诺
都参加了那次任务
were on the same mission.
麦克利什不是什么战争英雄
MacLeish isn't a war hero.
他是战争犯
He's a war criminal.
汉娜·威尔士  联邦调查局探员
Hannah Wells, an FBI agent,
她跟我说她有证据指证彼得·麦克利什
told me she had evidence against Peter MacLeish.
门禁卡有没有线索
Were you able to find out about the key card?
它能打开路易斯安娜电力通讯公司大楼
It gives you access to room 7 on the 8th floor
八楼的七号房间
of the PLC Building.
距离国会大厦很近
Proximity to the Capitol,
可以直接瞄准讲台
direct line of sight to the platform.
恭喜你  副总统先生
Congratulations, Mr. Vice President.
他们要杀柯克曼
They're gonna kill Kirkman.
枪
Gun!
不
No!
艾丽克斯  你被击中了
Alex, you've been hit.
那不是我的血
That's not my blood.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
救命
Help!
他们在来的路上
They're on their way.
扫清道路
Clear the hall!
道路已扫清
Hallway clear!
我在左腋和锁骨之间发现了枪伤
I've got a GSW between the left axilla and clavicle.
病人神志清醒
Patient is alert and oriented.
血压  136  92
I got B.P. at 136/92,
心率  114  正常窦性心律
heart rate 114, normal sinus rhythm,
血氧饱和度  98%
SPO2 at 98%.
1  2  3
1... 2... 3...
交叉配血六个单位
Type and cross six units,
大口径静脉输注  最大滴速
two large-bore I.V.S wide-open.
在这里照床旁X光片
And get portable X-ray in here.
总统先生  如果没问题
Mr. President, we're gonna roll you over for a moment
我们要将你侧过来
if that's okay.
我来照些X光片
Yeah, I'm going to get X-ray.
好了  好了
It's okay, it's okay.
在这里  子弹可能是点3口径
Right there -- it could be a 30-caliber
或是黒视  甚至可达5.56毫米
or a Blackout, maybe even a 5.56.
看来没打中肩胛骨
It looks like it just missed the scapula.
再躺平
And down.
总统先生  我们要拍些X光片
Mr. President, we're gonna take some X-rays
来排除肺部或者血管的创伤
to rule out lung or vascular damage,
但看起来像是贯穿伤
but it looks like the bullet went straight through.
现在我们要清理并冲洗伤口
Now we're going to clean and irrigate,
请忍耐
so bear with us.
深呼吸  总统先生  会有些刺痛
Deep breaths, Mr. President. This will sting.
美国民众心情沉重地等待着消息
The American people somberly await the news
不知他们的总统是死是活
if their president is alive or dead.
突发新闻  柯克曼总统死了吗
我不管他怎么跟你说的
I don't care what he told you.
我告诉你  立马把那些消息撤下来
I'm telling you, take that crap off your air right now.
此举不仅不负责  还很危险
It's not just irresponsible, it's dangerous,
没人关心事后的更正
and nobody cares about a correction after the fact.
你可以从旁观者的角度进行推测
You can speculate from the outside looking in,
要是你还坚持这样报道
and if you keep it up,
就等着去关岛演你的单口相声吧
you can do your stand-ups from Guam.
不可理喻
Unbelievable.
为什么要这么久
What the hell is taking so long?
现在应该有消息了才对
We should have heard something by now.
-艾米丽  -怎么了
- Emily. - What?
我的天
Oh, my God.
会没事的
It's gonna be okay.
你可说不准
You don't know.
没人能说准
Nobody knows that.
不行  不能这么干
No, no, that -- that's unacceptable.
我要负责人每15分钟做一次全面汇报
I want a full report from the agent in charge every 15 minutes
直到枪手落网  明白了吗
until the shooter is in custody. Is that understood?
好
Okay.
国安局  联调局  所有当地执法机关
The NSA, FBI, every local law-enforcement
都在全面搜捕枪手
is on the hunt for the shooter.
他们认为他仍在市区
Now, they think he's in the metro area,
但这就跟大海捞针没什么区别
but that's like saying the needle's somewhere in the haystack.
你没事吧
You okay?
我们应该将要点
We should get talking points
向国会领袖  美国驻联合国代表团
to the Congressional leadership, the USUN,
以及代理内阁部长们简述
and the acting cabinet secretaries.
都处理好了
That's all been taken care of.
新闻办公室都搞定了
Communications took charge of that.
对  我会确保放出去的都是准确消息
Yeah, I'll make sure the accurate information is out there.
艾丽克斯
Alex?
柯克曼夫人
Mrs. Kirkman?
他怎么样了
How is he?
我们还在等X光的结果
We're waiting on the X-rays,
但子弹应该没有留在体内
but it seems like the bullet went in and out.
并且没伤到重要部位
It didn't hit anything vital.
我知道他想见你们所有人
Um, I know he wants to see all of you,
但拜托  请不要让他一下承受太多
but if we could please not overwhelm him.
别担心  没毒
Don't worry. It's safe.
是从街尾的咖啡店买的
We got it from the cafe down the street.
那么...
So...
你曾逃离一起事故的案发现场
you flee the scene of an accident.
那可是肇事逃逸的重罪
That's a felony hit-and-run.
你在弗雷德里克斯堡射杀了一名目击证人
You kill a man in Fredericksburg who's an eyewitness.
那起码也是过失杀人罪
That's gonna be manslaughter, at the very least.
然后你出现在
And then you show up
副总统的宣誓就职典礼上
to the vice president's swearing-in ceremony,
开了枪  身上还有这个
firing a gun and carrying this.
这是开枪者所在大楼的门禁卡
It's a key card to the building where the shots came from.
这是密谋杀害总统
That's conspiracy to kill the president.
是死刑
That's the death penalty.
我相信
Now, I want to believe
你对这一切都有合理的解释
that you have good reasons for all of this,
可你要是不跟我解释清楚
but if you don't tell me what they are,
我无法帮你离开这里
I can't help you walk out of here.
我在向你提供一线生机  汉娜
I'm offering you a lifeline, Hannah.
赶紧抓住
Take it.
我已经录过口供了
I've already made my statement.
再无其他话可说
I have nothing else to say.
真可惜
It's a shame,
看样子有人要因此
because someone is gonna waste away
把联邦监狱坐穿了
in federal prison for this.
所以你最好认真思考一下
So you better think hard about
接下来的事情该如何解决了
how you want this to play out,
因为随着时间的飞快流逝...
because your options...
可供你选择的余地将越来越小
are about to get real small, real fast.
指定幸存者
第一季 第十一集
原创翻译  双语字幕
知道是谁干的了吗
Do we know who did this?
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
联调局在彻底排查监控视频  先生
The FBI's combing through surveillance footage, sir.
他们正试图确认枪手身份
They're trying to get an I.D.
我们必须要稳定金融市场
We need to stabilize the markets.
翻译     石头  苏小黛   子V  薇薇安  星星与野狗
不然会乱套的
They're gonna go crazy.
今天已经收市了
Trading is already closed for the day.
我们今晚也会密切关注全球市场的情况
And we'll keep a close eye on the global markets tonight, sir.
翻译     胡说大王   斗斗   Michael   长颈鹿
我会向媒体发布一则声明
I should make a statement to the press.
很好
Right, of course.
要让全国民众知道我没事
Let the country know that I'm fine,
翻译     kiki考试加油   桃子   Silence   做回特工的尼基塔
一得到医生的允许
and I'll be back in the Oval Office
我便马上回总统办公室继续工作
as soon as the doctors clear me.
没问题  总统先生
Definitely, Mr. President.
校对     苏小黛   长颈鹿   MQ小早
别让我失望
Make me proud.
谢谢  先生
Thank you, sir.
-也谢谢你们  -是  先生
- Thank you. - Yes, sir.
时间轴     Avis   壬虚浪影   姜姜
天啊
Oh, my God.
后期     虫虫不咬人
是  当然
Yes, of course.
感谢上帝  好在他没事
I just thank the Lord he's okay.
总监     MQ小早
好  我会坚守自己岗位
Yeah, I'll hold the fort down on my end.
好的
Okay.
感谢你的来电
Thank you for calling.
他还活着
He's alive.
子弹直接贯穿
Bullet went straight through,
没有造成持续性损害
no lasting damage.
为什么会这样
How the hell does this happen?
放轻松  好吗
Just relax, all right?
在我们被怀疑之前
We need to wash our hands of this right now,
别再淌这趟浑水了
before it gets back to us.
撒手不干吗
Wash our hands of this?
彼得  手上的血腥味是洗不掉的
Peter, blood doesn't wash out, it stains,
这也是我们一直在向前进的原因
which is why we keep moving forward.
这只是个小插曲罢了
It's just a setback.
-万一他们抓到洛萨诺了呢  -不会的
- And what if they catch Lozano? - They won't.
他训练有素  你也是
He was trained for this, so were you.
你们并肩作战过  还记得吗
Brothers in arms, remember?
况且这次任务  也没有完全失败
And the mission didn't entirely fail,
难道不是吗  副总统先生
did it... Mr. Vice President?
汉娜·威尔士
Hannah Wells?
-他们抓到的是她吗  -是的  先生
- That's who they have in custody? - Yes, sir.
我和法索部长谈过了
I spoke with Director Foerstel,
就在她开枪之后
and District Police picked her up
警察在狙击手出现地附近
in the proximity of the sniper
逮捕了她
just after she discharged her weapon.
麦克  我知道你想留在这里陪我
Mike, I know you think you have to be here with me,
但我不会有事的
but I'm gonna be fine.
我真正需要的是
What I really need you to do is
你去找她谈谈
go down there and talk to her
弄清楚她到底知道什么
and find out what she knows.
这是让我们查出
It's the only chance we have of finding out
事情真相的唯一机会
what the hell is going on.
遵命
Yes, sir.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我真的很抱歉
I'm so, so sorry.
他还活着  这才是最重要的
He's alive. That's all that matters.
怎么回事
W-What is it?
我知道现在不是个好时候
I know this isn't the right time,
但昨天  总统要我
but yesterday, the president asked me
调查一项高级机密
to look into a highly classified situation.
-我知道  -好的
- I know. - Okay.
你发现什么了吗
Did you find anything?
我想是的
I think so.
曾有一通从白宫打出的电话  要求撤回
Um, there was a call made from the White House
国会大厦的威胁评估报告
to kill the report.
那个电话是从亚伦办公室打出的
And that call came from Aaron's office.
-什么  -我知道
- What? - I know.
我曾试图知会总统
I was trying to tell the president,
但却来不及了
but I couldn't get to him in time,
-我不知道该怎么办  -没事
- and I don't know what -- what do I do? - Oh, okay.
你不能让亚伦靠近我的丈夫  明白吗
You need to keep Aaron away from my husband, okay?
-你明白吗  -是的
- Have you got that? - Yes.
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
总统先生  我需要和你谈谈
Mr. President, I need to talk to you
最新的CT扫描结果
about your latest C.T. scans, sir.
-怎么了  有问题吗  -是的
- Why? Is there a problem? - Yes.
结果显示有几块子弹碎片残留在你的胸腔里
It shows several bullet fragments lodged in your chest.
一旦有碎片移位
If one were to dislodge,
就可能切断你的大动脉  危及生命
it could sever your aorta and prove fatal.
总统先生  我们需要尽快动手术
Sir, we need to operate as soon as possible.
好的  我明白了
Okay. I understand.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我们马上开始准备手术室
We'll start prepping the O.R.
谢谢你  总统先生
Thank you, sir.
我们需要谈一下
We need to talk.
看来我还是得动手术
It looks like I'm going to have to go into surgery after all.
我会被全身麻醉至少三个小时
I'll be under general anesthetic for at least three hours.
对此情况的处理标准是什么
What's the protocol for that?
总统先生  如果您失去了意识
Well, sir, if you're unconscious,
就意味着您没有办法
that means you'll be incapable
正常履行总统职责
to discharge your duties as president.
所以我们就得启用第25号修正案
So we'll have to invoke the 25th Amendment.
好的  我们要怎么做
Okay, how do we do that?
我们要通过一份签好字的声明
We'll notify the Speaker of the House
书面知会众议院议长和
and the president pro tempore of the Senate
参议院临时议长
through a signed and written statement
说明您将暂时离开总统办公室
that you'll be temporarily vacating the office.
彼得·麦克利什将成为代理总统
And Peter MacLeish will be acting president.
我马上为您联系上副总统  总统先生
I'll set up a call with you and the V.P. immediately, sir.
不  我想和霍斯拉滕议长谈谈
No. I want to talk to Speaker Hookstraten.
长官
Sir?
尽快叫金布尔过来
Get Kimble here as quickly as possible.
好的  总统先生
Yes, sir.
谢谢你
Thank you.
霍斯拉滕  这是怎么回事
Hookstraten? What's that all about?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
提醒一下  历史上曾多次
So, just a reminder -- the 25th Amendment has been invoked
启用第25号修正案
several times in the past.
里根总统和第43任总统布什都曾经
Both Presidents Reagan and Bush 43
临时将权力移交给副总统
temporarily transferred power to their vice presidents,
所以这不是什么空前之举
so this is not unprecedented.
加里  请说
Yes, Gary?
这样一个大手术的成功几率是多少
Do we know what the odds are for a major surgery like this?
就病人存活率来说
I mean, in terms of patient survival.
我不打算现在就回答这个问题
So, I'm not prepared to answer that right now,
但是医疗队伍将会在
but the medical team is gonna be briefing the press pool
成功完成柯克曼总统的手术后
after the successful completion
向众位记者做简报
of President Kirkman's surgery.
在那之前  我只会按需告知你们最新进展
Until then, I'll just be updating you on as-needed basis.
谢莉
Shelly?
总统情况怎么样
How are the president's spirits?
综合来看  他还不错
You know, all things considered, he's doing well.
他正在休息  并集中精力管理国家
He's resting and focusing on the business of running the country.
容我再问一句
Just a quick follow-up.
总统跟麦克利什副总统谈过了吗
Has the president spoken to Vice President MacLeish yet?
就算还没谈过
If that hasn't already happened,
在总统进手术室之前
then, uh, it will be taking place
也一定会找他谈的
before President Kirkman goes into surgery.
先生
Sir?
能让我们单独谈谈吗
Can I have the room, please.
总统先生  你感觉怎么样
Mr. President, how are you feeling?
就像被枪击了一样
Like I've been shot.
至少你的幽默感还在
Well, at least your sense of humor is still intact.
金布尔  我准备启用第25号修正案
Kimble, I'm gonna have to invoke the 25th Amendment,
让彼得·麦克利什成为总统
which means that Peter MacLeish will be president.
持续多久
For how long?
我不知道
I don't know.
虽然我们并不总是政见相同
We haven't always agreed on everything,
但我一直知道你心向国家
but I've always felt that your heart was in the right place.
我想请你帮我盯着副总统
I need you to keep an eye on the vice president,
确保他的所作所为都是为了国家的最优利益
make sure he's working in the country's best interests,
而不是为了他自己
not his own.
你明白我的意思吗
You understand what I'm saying?
明白  先生
I do, sir.
我就指望你了
I'm counting on you.
我不会让你失望的  总统先生
I won't let you down, Mr. President.
上次谈话之后  她有说过什么吗
Has she said anything since we spoke?
恐怕没有
No, afraid not.
如果可以的话  我想审讯她
I'd like to question her, if it's all right.
要是在别的情况下
You know, under any other circumstances,
我会拒绝你
I'd have to say no.
不过这一切都说不通
But nothing about this makes any sense.
或许她会对你开口
Maybe she'll talk to you.
谢谢
Thanks.
先说清楚
Just so we're clear,
如果她透露了什么  你要告诉我
if she gives you anything, you share it with me.
下午好
Good afternoon.
我是麦克·里特  特勤处的
My name is Mike Ritter, Secret Service.
我是负责保护总统个人安全的安保人员
I'm assigned to the president's personal protection detail.
昨天  由于霍斯拉滕议长说起过你
Yesterday you were brought to the president's attention
你引起了总统的主意
by Speaker Hookstraten.
她说在麦克利什副总统就职前
She said you claimed to have had information
你声称有关于他的消息
about Vice President MacLeish before he was confirmed.
总统想知道是什么消息
The president would like to know what that information was.
威尔士探员  你必须回答我的问题
Agent Wells, you need to answer my question.
不  我不需要
No, I don't.
为什么
And why is that?
因为我不了解你
Because I don't know you.
如果总统想要答案
And if the president wants answers,
我只会告诉一个人
I'll give them to one person --
总统本人
the president himself.
过来
Come here.
我会没事的  你别担心
I'm gonna be fine. I don't want you to worry.
总统先生  时间到了
Mr. President, it's time, sir.
抱歉夫人  我们现在得送他进手术室了
Sorry, ma'am, we need to take him now.
静脉注射已准备就绪
I.V. wide-open.
准备吧
Go ahead, set it up.
他们将会给您注射麻醉剂
They're going to administer the anesthetic.
然后请您从100开始倒数
And then I'll ask you to please count down backwards from 100.
100...
...99...
...98...
...97...
...96...
...95...
总统失去意识了
The president is unconscious.
先生  你现在是美国代理总统了
Sir, you're now the acting president of the United States.
四号剥离器  谢谢
Number 4 dissector, please.
-给  医生  -谢谢
- Here, Doctor. - Thank you.
-抽  -再来点纱布
- Suction. - More gauze.
-纱布和手术钳  -排放情况如何
- Gauze and forceps. - How's the drainage?
这里  好  稳住
Right there. Good. Hold it.
这可是很精细的手术  彼得
It's delicate surgery, Peter.
要是他撑不过来
If he doesn't survive it,
我们就没什么可担心的了
then we have nothing to worry about.
事情就都回到正轨了
We are right back on track.
好的
Okay.
洛扎诺还在外头呢
Well, Lozano is still out there.
联调局  国安部
FBI, Homeland...
肯定已经有人有了关于他的线索
someone must have a lead on him by now.
那么  作为代理总统
And then, as acting president,
你可以坚持让他们直接向你汇报
you can insist they report directly to you.
要是他们抓住或是接近了他
If they catch him or get close,
你就可以第一时间下达命令
you'll be right there to issue your orders.
那要是总统在那之前醒过来呢
And what if the president wakes up before then?
你至少还有几个小时呢
You've got at least a few hours.
好好利用吧
Make the most of them.
-好吧  -先生
- Okay. - Sir?
里边需要您  就现在
You're needed inside now.
-一会儿见  -好
- See you later. - Yeah.
好了  大家
All right, everyone,
现在请所有人注意这边
I need all eyes and ears over here right now, please.
谁先说
Who's first?
副总统先生
Mr. Vice President,
亚洲市场持续下滑
Asian markets are in free fall.
总统手术的消息一出
The Nikkei and Hang Seng opened down almost 2,000 points
日经和恒生开盘跌了快两千点了
on reports of the president's surgery.
我们需要证交委明天继续关停股市
We need the SEC to keep stock markets closed tomorrow.
不行  这不是个好主意
Uh, no, that's not a good idea.
抱歉  副总统先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Vice President,
但即便有下限条款来抑制市场恐慌
but even with circuit breaks in place to halt market panic,
仅一成的下跌就能让民众损失几十亿
just a 10% drop will wipe billions from people's accounts.
那可是养老金和529计划的大学基金
That's pensions and 529 college funds.
她说的没错  先生
And she's right, sir.
几小时的损失要花几年去弥补
What's lost in hours can take years to regain.
我明白  但你们说的是市场力量
I understand, but you're talking about market forces.
现在不是2008年了
This isn't 2008.
银行不会破产
Banks aren't failing.
玩儿的是心理学  是从众心理
It's psychology. It's herd mentality.
要是股票下跌
If there is a sell-off,
那就是个买入的机会  市场就会回弹
then it's a buying opportunity and the market bounces back.
我们得让全世界知道
We need to tell the world
美国经济一切如常
that America is open for business.
抱歉  先生  市场可不喜欢不确定因素
Excuse me, sir, the markets hate uncertainty.
你这是在鼓励恐慌抛售
You're just encouraging panic selling.
我觉得"一切如常"可以安抚民情
Well, I think people are comforted by routine.
如果我们表现得慌张  舆论也会如此
If we act like we're panicked, then opinion will follow.
好了  枪手的事怎么样了
Okay, where are we with the shooter?
有个停车场上报有车被盗
A vehicle was reported stolen from a parking garage
距射击地点两个街区
two blocks from the shooting site.
区警从事发地的监控摄像
District Police recovered an image
恢复出了一张图像
from the lot's surveillance camera
正试图查证是否与目击人的描述相吻合
and are trying to see if it matches eyewitness description.
-好极了  -与此同时
- Great. - In the meantime,
我们正在跟联合战术行动中心合作追捕枪手
we're coordinating our manhunt from the CTOC --
不行
No.
让他们来这里跟白宫指挥中心合作
Have CTOC coordinate with Command Ops here in the White House.
长官  联战中心完全有能力
Sir, CTOC is perfectly capable
处理这种行动
of handling an operation like that.
我知道  但我有责任保护这个国家
I know, but I have a responsibility to protect this country,
而我不想通过电话来指挥
and I don't want to be doing that over the phone.
等我们找到那个
I want to be right here with you
试图杀他的混蛋时  我要跟你们一起在场
when we find the monster that tried to kill him.
-是  长官  -好
- Yes, sir. - Okay.
下一位
Who's next?
威尔士探员
Agent Wells...
有新消息了
I've got an update for you.
我可以走了吗
I'm free to go?
不是这事
Not exactly.
是关于你跟总统面谈的事
It's about your sit-down with the president.
太好了  他什么时候过来
Great. When's he getting here?
恐怕没那么简单
Afraid it's not gonna be that simple.
总统现在正在接受手术
The President's undergoing surgery right now.
他不得不启动第25号修正案
He had to invoke the 25th.
第25号修正案
The 25th?
等等  彼得·麦克利什现在是总统了吗
Wait a minute. Peter MacLeish is the president?
是的
Yeah.
汉娜
Hannah...
最新海外影视剧下载
告诉我你找到的有关彼得·麦克利什的证据
tell me what evidence you have against Peter MacLeish.
霍斯拉滕议长找你  先生
Speaker Hookstraten to see you, sir.
有什么能效劳的  金布尔
What can I do for you, Kimble?
你可以告诉我你到底打的什么鬼主意
You can tell me what the hell's going on in your mind.
你明明知道如果明天开放市场
You know if you open those markets tomorrow,
就会天下大乱
it'll be a disaster.
不  我不知道
No, I don't.
还有  你别忘了
And in case you've forgotten,
你这是在代理总统的办公室里
you're addressing the office of the acting president.
彼得
You know, Peter,
你刚来国会的时候
when you first arrived in Congress,
我觉得你很  普通
I thought you were, well... ordinary --
又一个兴高采烈的首次当选的人
another first-termer just happy to be there,
一个成就远超乎了
a man whose achievements had far outstripped
自己想象的人
even his own imagination.
但我现在才意识到
But I realize now
我低估了你
that I'd underestimated you --
你的欲望  你的野心
your drive, your ambition.
你一点也不普通
There's nothing ordinary about you.
谢谢  谢谢你这么说
Well, thank you. I appreciate you saying that.
记住  我会一直盯着你的
Just know I'll be watching you.
别人可能会被今天的事分心
Others may be distracted by what's happening today,
但我不会
but not me.
如果我发现有什么不正常
If I see anything out of step,
我会把我的怀疑直接告诉白宫记者团
I'll take my suspicions straight to the White House press corps.
你是在威胁我吗
Are you threatening me?
绝对是  总统先生
Absolutely... sir.
不好意思  长官  找到枪手了
Excuse me, sir. They found the shooter.
他们在指挥中心等你
They're waiting for you at Command Ops.
我马上就到
I'll be right there.
金布尔  谢谢你的来访
And, Kimble... thanks for coming by.
威尔士探员  拜托
Agent Wells, please.
你要跟议长说什么有关彼得·麦克利什的事
What were you gonna tell the speaker about Peter MacLeish?
跟之前你在弗雷德里克斯堡郊外
Does it have something to do with --
射杀的这个人有关系吗
with this man that you shot outside Fredericksburg?
或者这个人  我们
Or this guy? We --
我们还不知道他的名字
we haven't found a name for him yet.
我们认为他就是向柯克曼总统开枪的人
We believe he's responsible for shooting President Kirkman.
你认识他吗
Do you know him?
汉娜
Hannah?
威尔士探员  你认得这个男人吗
Agent Wells, do you recognize this man?
让我帮你
好吧
All right.
我可是尽力了
Can't say I didn't try.
也许法索对你的看法是对的
You know, maybe Foerstel's right about you.
妄想症毁了你
Your paranoia got the best of you.
赶紧派人进去
Get everybody in here now!
找到恰克·拉辛克  问他关于卡特兰的事
Find Chuck Russink. Ask about Catalan.
放开他  放开他
Let him go! Let him go!
够了
That's it!
把她带出去
Get her out of here.
没事  坐着吧  谢谢你们
It's fine. Stay seated. Thank you.
局长
Director.
先生  已跟踪疑犯到海军陆战队一处军备库
Sir, suspect was tracked to a marine storage facility.
他藏在里面
He's barricaded himself inside.
有别的出口吗
Any other way out?
没有  我们把他包围了
No, sir. We've got him surrounded.
疑犯受过专业的规避战术
Suspect appears to be highly trained
与作战技能的训练
in evasive tactics and combat skills.
可能现役或曾服役于特种部队
Could be Special Forces, or was at one time.
下令逮捕
Give the order to apprehend.
开始围捕
Proceed with apprehension.
你说什么
Excuse me?
这是标准操作规程  先生
It's standard operating procedure, sir.
如遇反抗可使用致命武力
Deadly force to be applied if defense,
但若非如此  我们要活捉疑犯
but, in all other cases, we take our suspects alive.
不  这样不对
No, that's a mistake.
什么
Sir?
不能为了活捉一名杀手
There's no reason to put good men at risk
而将我们的人置于险境
trying to apprehend an assassin.
如果行动中有人看见疑犯
If anyone on the ground gets this man in their sights,
立刻射杀
I want him taken out.
-副总统先生...  -这是我的决定
- Mr. Vice President... - That's my decision.
下达命令吧
Give the order.
柯克曼总统会想要生擒他的  先生
President Kirkman would have wanted to take him alive, sir.
你又不知道
You don't know that.
-我很肯定  -好吧
- I believe I do. - Okay.
他想问的问题只有枪手能回答
He'll want answers to questions only the shooter can give.
所以我们才活捉了纳萨尔
That's why we took Nassar alive.
我不同意
I disagree.
下达命令吧  就地射杀
Give the order. Shoot to kill.
准备处决疑犯
Prepare to execute.
收到
Copy that.
准备进入
Prepare to enter.
副总统先生
Mr. Vice President,
我反对此番作战计划
I'm advising against this course of action,
-强烈反对  -知道了
- in the strongest of terms. - Noted.
我对你与总统先生均负有责任...
I have a duty, sir, to you and the president...
你已经做得很好了
And you've... you've carried it out.
下达命令
Give the order.
就地射杀
Shoot to kill.
收到  就地射杀
Roger that. Shoot to kill.
就地射杀
Shoot to kill.
收到  就地射杀
Roger. Shoot to kill.
-开火  -行动  行动  行动
- Open fire. - Execute, execute, execute.
目标已倒下  静止不动
Target's down. He's not moving.
目标已歼灭
Target neutralized.
等待确认
Stand by for confirmation.
目标已歼灭
Target is neutralized.
收到
Roger that.
目标已歼灭
Target is neutralized.
柯克曼总统的手术已经进行了一个多小时
We're now over an hour into President Kirkman's surgery,
目前没有消息就是好消息
and so far, no news seems to be good news.
以此同时  祈福者们持续从四面八方赶来
Meanwhile, well-wishers continue to pour in from all over,
放置鲜花  高举标语
laying flowers, holding signs,
祈祷他们的总统快点好起来
and praying for a swift recovery of their president.
按压这里
Keep pressure down in there, please.
说出来你都不信
So, you won't believe this.
麦吉本刚告诉我曼哈顿儿童权益基金会
McKibben just told me that Manhattan Children's Rights Fund
需要一个新的首席顾问
needs a new chief counsel.
而且他推荐了我
And he's recommending me.
你是个勇士
You're a warrior.
他知道这点
He knows it.
纽约每一个律师事务所都知道
So does every law firm in New York.
才没有
No.
今天过得怎么样
How was your day?
有意思
Interesting.
我也收到一份工作邀约
I got a job offer, too.
我要猜
Don't tell me.
他们想让你当部门主管
They want you to chair the department.
不是
No.
是总统[主席]给的工作
It was from the president.
什么主席
The president of what?
美国总统
The United States.
他想让我当住房与城市发展部的部长
He wants me to come on as HUD secretary.
-什么  -他说他真的很喜欢
- What? - He said he was really taken
我做的关于福德公园的住房计划
by my housing initiative in Bedford Park
我的新鲜点子能为他的内阁所用
and that he thought his cabinet could use fresh ideas like mine.
那你答应了吧
Well, y-y-you said yes, right?
没  我想跟你商量商量
No, I wanted to talk to you about it.
有什么好商量的
What is there to talk about?
汤姆  你必须答应
Tom, you have to do this.
这是搞政治
It's politics.
我得作演讲  谈妥协
I'd have to make speeches, compromise.
我是说我甚至可能得支持
I mean, I might even have to stand behind something
自己根本不相信的东西
I don't even believe in.
我是搞城市规划的  是个建筑师
I'm an urban planner, an architect.
不是政治家
I'm not a politician.
汤姆   这可是美国总统
Tom, the president of the United States
请你为他工作
is asking you to serve.
这是千载难逢的机会啊
This is an opportunity of a lifetime.
我们得搬家
We'd have to move.
孩子们要找新学校  一切重头开始
The kids would have to find new schools, start over.
我们都会
We all would.
这真的会改变我们的生活
This would really change our lives.
以一种我们无法想象的方式
In ways that we can't even imagine.
好吧  还有时间去拒绝
Okay... ...there are times to say no,
但拒绝可不是选项之一
but this is not one of them.
勇士  对吧
Warriors, right?
对
Yeah.
勇士
Warriors.
女士  我想你可能需要这个
Ma'am, I thought you might need this.
谢谢  赛斯
Thank you, Seth.
-有任何消息吗  -没有
- So, any news? - No.
你该走了  该回家了
You should go. You should go home.
错过这些免费的咖啡吗  才不要
And miss out on all this free coffee? Come on.
况且  我还得顾着外面那些记者们
Besides, I've still got to babysit these reporters outside.
-好吧  坐下来跟我说说话吧  -好啊
- Well, sit down and talk to me. - Sure.
说什么呢
About what?
什么都行
Anything.
跟这些无关的
Apart from, you know.
你有女朋友吗
Do you have a girlfriend?
没有
No.
想找个吗
Do you want one?
现在不想
Not right now.
为什么不呢
Why not?
只是时机不凑巧
Just doesn't seem like it's a good time.
这个理由太站不住脚了
That's a terrible excuse.
人生大事总该花点时间的
You always need to make time for the things that are important.
夫人  我现在所做的就是大事
Ma'am, what I do is important.
如果只能孤军奋战  那就不是了
But not if you're doing it alone.
这都是我的错
This is all my fault.
他本来不想在住房和城市发展部就职
He didn't want the job at HUD.
是我非让他去的
I made him take it.
是我的企图心作祟
I was the ambitious one.
然而现在...看吧
And now...look.
夫人  您不能因那件事而自责
Ma'am, you can't blame yourself for that.
他会没事的
He's gonna be okay.
恰克·拉辛克
Chuck Russink?
我知道你在里面
I know you're inside.
你是谁
Who is it?
麦克·里特  特勤局特工
Agent Mike Ritter, Secret Service.
美国特勤局
有何贵干
What do you want?
我想和你谈谈汉娜·威尔士的事
I want to talk to you about Hannah Wells.
我应经向法索部长交代了
I already told Director Foerstel
我不知道她在哪
I don't know where she is.
这不是我要问的  我们知道她在哪
That's not the problem. We know where she is.
我要的是她手上关于彼得·麦克利什的证据
I'm interested in what she knows about Peter MacLeish.
证件可以伪造
Anyone can get an I.D. Like that.
我凭什么给你开门
Why the hell should I open the door for you?
如果你不开门  我会把它踹开
Because if you don't, I'll just kick it in.
好吧  给我个理由
Yeah, well, convince me.
让我放你进来
Tell me why - I should let you inside.
卡特兰
Catalan.
什么
What?
威尔士亲口告诉我的
Wells gave me a message.
她让我向你打听卡特兰的事情
She told me to ask you about Catalan.
现在相信了
Convinced now?
是的
Yeah.
许多华尔街人士推测
Many on Wall Street are speculating
明日的证券市场
that tomorrow's markets
国际市场
国外市场跌至历史新低
将面临2010年闪电崩盘以来
will experience the steepest nosedive
最大的暴跌
since the Flash Crash of 2010.
投资者们正纷纷转投资产
Investors are turning to assets...
在局势不确定的时期
...that are seen as safer bets
这不失为一个更安全的选择
in times of uncertainty. For --
亚伦·肖尔
Aaron Shore.
是的
Yeah.
什么
What?!
我要看总统先生
I need to see the President's schedule
未来三天的日程安排
for the next 72 hours
以确定哪些要取消哪些要代理
to know what to cancel and what to surrogate.
这是柯克曼一家所有成员及朋友的名单
This is a list of all the Kirkmans' family and friends.
打给他们以免听信电视新闻里的谣言
Please call them so they're not hearing things from the TV.
-同时要安排通讯部门... -艾米丽
- I'm also going to need Comms -- - Emily,
-我需要和你谈谈  拜托  -稍等
- I'm gonna need a word with you, please. - One second.
我们需要通讯部门为接线总机处和批文办
We need Comms to draft talking points
拟定谈话要点
for the switchboard and the protocol office.
今天一定会有成千上万的来电
There are gonna be thousands of phone calls coming in today,
一定要让他们知道该如何答复民众
and we're gonna need them to know what to tell people.
明白了吗  谢谢
Okay? Thanks.
里面谈
In here.
你要谈什么
What is it?
应该是你告诉我发生了什么吧
You feel like telling me what's going on?
你指的是什么
What are you talking about?
我刚刚和白宫档案室通完电话
I just got off the phone with the White House archives.
他们在问我是否授权你
They were asking me if I had authorized you
查看我两年前的个人电话记录
to look at my personal phone logs from two years ago.
那我再问一次
All right, so, I'll ask again.
发生什么事了  艾米丽
What's going on, Emily?
-这肯定是沟通失误  -是吗
- It must have been a miscommunication. - Yeah, right.
就像那天你告诉我  你工作得很晚
Like the other day when you told me you were working late
因为总统在重新考虑
because the president was having second thoughts
他对城市发展部长的选择
on his choice - for the HUD secretary --
而总统却对此事一无所知
something the president knew nothing about?
怎么  那也是沟通失误吗
What, was that a miscommunication, too?
告诉我  艾米丽  出什么事了
Talk to me, Emily. What's going on?
我无权讨论这件事
I'm not at liberty to discuss this.
-对不起  -你无...
- I'm sorry. - You're not at --
这话到底是什么意思
What the -- What the hell is that supposed to mean?
意思就是我不能和你讨论这件事
It means I can't talk about this with you.
这是我和总统之间的事
It is between me and the president.
和我有关的事吗
About me?
我无权讨论
I'm not at liberty to discuss.
-抱歉  -艾米丽  等等
- Excuse me. - E-Emily, wait.
你在调查我吗
Are -- Are you investigating me?
你应该等总统回来再和他说
You should wait to talk to the president when he gets back.
对不起  我不能再说了
I'm sorry. I can't say any more.
重要器官情况如何
How's vitals?
情况稳定  但还很脆弱
It's steady, but he's still a bit tacky.
尽量避免伤及主要血管
Minimal tearing in the major vessels.
-在夹子上方切个口子  -好
- Make a cut above the clamp. - Yep.
很好
Good. Okay.
再加一袋血
Let's hang another bag.
心律升至136
Heart rate increasing, 136.
-氧气饱和指数95%  -我要再做减压
- O2 sat's now 95%. - I'm taking another pressure.
其中一个碎片肯定擦伤了动脉
One of the fragments must have nicked an artery.
抽吸
Suction.
血压下降  74至98
His pressure is dropping -- 98/74.
吸血棉  再来点
Sponges. More sponges.
再拿吸血棉来
More sponges. Keep them coming.
找到源头  否则他会失血致死
We got to find the source, or he's gonna bleed out.
没错  这是卡特兰
Yeah. That's Catalan.
他和彼得·麦克利什曾在同一个陆军部队服役
He was in the same army unit as Peter MacLeish.
汉娜发现了这点
That's what Hannah uncovered.
那你是说副总统
So, you're saying the vice president
与企图刺杀总统的人有关联吗
is linked to the man who tried to assassinate the president?
她有证据吗
She got proof?
原来有的
She had proof,
但是被人从她车里偷走了
but it was stolen from her car.
偷走了
Stolen?
那些机密文件里还有更多的证据
You know, there's more out there in some very classified files.
但愿你真的是为总统效力
So I hope you really do work for the president,
否则我们就是在浪费时间
or we're wasting our time here.
加两包红血球  立刻
Hang two units packed red blood cells -- stat!
马上  医生
Right away, Doctor.
清理手术区
I need to clean the field.
重要器官情况稳定
Vitals stabilizing.
好
Okay.
他已脱离危险期
He's out of the woods.
好了  缝合伤口
All right, let's close him up.
你怎么在外面
What are you doing out here?
很安静
It's quiet.
柯克曼还在做手术吗
Kirkman still in surgery?
出现了并发症
Um, there was a complication,
但似乎会渡过危机
but, uh, it looks like he'll pull through.
我们也会
So will we.
你怎么能如此确定
How the hell can you be so sure of that?
因为他没有我们的把柄
Because he's got nothing on us.
卡特兰已经死了
Catalan is dead.
能把你和他联系起来的证据
The evidence connecting you and him
已经不存在了
doesn't exist anymore.
放松  彼得
Breathe, Peter.
各项事务都妥善处理了
Everything is being handled accordingly.
那霍斯拉滕怎么办
And what about Hookstraten?
她怎么了
What about her?
她盯着我的一举一动
She's watching my every move.
当我施压证券交易委员会
She questioned me
要求开市的时候  她质疑我
when I forced the SEC to keep the markets open.
如果她发现了原因
If she figures out why --
她不会的
She won't.
有可能的
She might.
没人能动我们  我告诉过你
Nothing can touch us. I told you that.
如果她成了问题  就把她也除掉
And if she's a problem, we remove her, too.
他们有没有说还要多久
So, how much longer are they saying it's gonna be?
没说  但是说他情况很不错
They're not, but they say he's doing fine.
希望他们可以很快完成手术
But, hopefully, they're gonna be finished up soon.
佩妮睡了吗
Is Penny asleep?
看了两本书  然后电影看到一半就睡着了
Only took about two books and half a movie,
我把她安顿好了
but I got her down.
什么电影
Which movie?
-《荒野猎人》  -什么
- “The Revenant." - W-What?
开玩笑
I'm just kidding.
就是个什么公主动画片
Just some cartoon princess movie.
陪看很痛苦
It was painful.
你是最棒的
Well, you're the best.
谢谢  亲爱的
Thank you so much, sweetie.
我为你感到骄傲
I'm really proud of you.
小事一桩
It was nothing.
我们都在做之前没做过的事  对吧
I mean, we're all doing jobs we weren't doing before, right?
妈妈
Mom?
你还好吗
You okay?
还好
Yeah.
我很好
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
我得挂了
Hey, I-I got to hang up.
医生来了
The doctor's coming.
我待会儿再打给你好吗
I'll call you right back, okay?
汤姆
Hey, Tom.
亲爱的
Honey.
当全世界都等着进一步了解总统现状的时候
As the world waits for further word on the president's condition,
所有主要指数都在继续暴跌
all major indices are continuing to plunge.
道琼斯指数  纳斯达克  标准普尔
The Dow, NASDAQ, and S&P
都已经跌至接近黑色星期一
are approaching Black Monday-type losses.
1987年10月19日 纽约股票交易所历史上单日跌幅最大的一天。
道琼斯工业平均指数
The Dow Jones Industrial Average
在柯克曼总统枪击案之后一天内
has already plunged a staggering 2,000 points in one day,
暴跌了惊人的两千点
after the shooting of President Kirkman.
你吃的最好别是我的果冻
You better not be eating my jello.
那是我的果冻  我辛苦赚来的
It's my jello. I earned it.
早上好
Good morning.
医生怎么说
What did the doctors say?
他们已经移除了所有子弹碎片
They removed all the bullet fragments,
并且说没有造成任何永久性损伤
and they say there is no permanent damage.
很好
Good.
我昨晚一直听到走廊上有声音
Last night, I kept hearing voices out in the hall.
是他们来看你怎么样了
It was just people coming by to see how you were.
国家反应如何
How is the country reacting?
汤姆  你现在不需要操心那些
Tom, you don't need to worry about that now.
好吧
Okay.
麦克利什开市了
MacLeish opened the markets.
华尔街人心惶惶  股市直线下跌
Wall Street's in a panic, and stocks are plummeting.
他为什么要这么做
Why the hell would he do that?
我们必须要恢复自信
We need to restore confidence.
怎么做  汤姆
Well, Tom, how?
你还在病榻上
You're on your back.
拜托  艾丽克斯
Come on, Alex.
我们是勇士  对吗
Warriors, right?
快  扶我起来
Come on, help me up.
不  我们没有遮遮掩掩  我告诉你了
No, we're not hiding anything. Look, I already told you.
总统已经脱离了危险
The president is out of surgery
正在休息静养  艾米丽
and he's resting comfortably. Emily?
-第25号修正案撤回了吗  -是的
- Has the 25th Amendment been revoked? - Yes.
一旦总统能够联系到
As soon as the president was able to reach
霍斯拉滕议长和参议院
Speaker Hookstraten and the Senate pro tem,
他就会继续行使总指挥的权力  加里
he resumed his duties as commander in chief. Gary?
赛斯  已经两天了  我们什么时候能见他
Seth, it's been two days. When can we see him?
-只要他的医生同意  -那是什么时候
- As soon as his doctors say so. - When is that gonna be?
人民需要知道他们的总统现在怎么样了
The people need to know what condition their president's in.
我已经回答过这个问题了
I already answered that question.
如果各位有
Look, if any of you have questions
我还未回答过的问题  请尽管提问
I haven't already answered, please feel free to ask.
看那里
Over here! Look, over there!
总统出现在病房窗口
这就是今天早些时候发生的一幕
And that was the scene earlier today
在乔治华盛顿大学医疗中心
at George Washington University Medical Center
柯克曼总统在接受了重大手术几个小时之后
as President Kirkman waved to an adoring crowd,
向支持他的群众挥手致意
just hours after his life-threatening surgery.
全世界他的生命安危的关注
After all the worldwide concerns about his health
导致全球经济市场混乱之后
plunged the global financial markets into chaos,
这无疑是
this was, indeed,
一个充满了希望和信心的特别时刻
an extraordinary moment of hope and assurance.
很快
Immediately afterwards,
道琼斯指数和标准普尔指数开始反弹
the DOW and S&P began to rebound,
全盘飘红
and showing significant gains across the board.
柯克曼总统
President Kirkman
道琼斯指数已经上升450点
The Dow is up 450 points.
标准普尔指数上涨7%
S&P is up 7%.
看起来这手挥得值  总统先生
Looks like your wave paid off, sir.
这是个好消息
That's great news,
但是我们还有很多事情要做
but we've still got a lot of work to do.
你还要慢慢恢复身体
You still have a lot of recovery to do.
这个也很重要
And that, too.
亚伦呢
Where's Aaron?
他回办公室
He's back at the office,
处理一些琐事了
just finishing up a few things.
打扰了  总统先生
Excuse me, Mr. President.
好的
Right.
请各位回避一下
Can I have a moment, please?
谢谢
Thank you.
她来了吗
Is she here?
是的  总统先生
Yes, sir.
带她进来
Bring her in.
所有人都出去
Clear the floor!
没关系  麦克
It's all right, Mike.
威尔士探员
Agent Wells.
总统先生
Mr. President.
我知道你想告诉我一些
I understand you have some things
关于彼得·麦克利什的事情
you want to tell me about Peter MacLeish.
是的  总统先生
Yes, sir. I do.
那我们开始吧
Then we should get started.